# Mahendra Kuruswamy 🕡 Featured

Developer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Web Development, UI Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS



Current Designation: UI Developer Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Web Development, UI Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality

Management, Requirement Gathering, JavaScript, Bootstrap, MongoDB, HTML, CSS

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

### Summary

Total 9 years of experience as UI/Front-end-developer

Expertise in developing Web Applications using HTML (4/5), CSS (2/3), JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular (2/6), jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, JSON,

Expertise in Angular 2 & 4, NGRX Platform (Store, Effects, Router-Store, Store-Devtools), RXJS, TypeScript,.

Knowledge of PHP, MySQL, Code ignitor MVC, Python Frame Work Flask.

Knowledge of Databases like MongoDB, SQL Server.

To pursue a successful career in software development, utilizing critical thinking and superb skills in developing applications by means of the most modern of development tools.

## **Work Experience**

Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd as UI Developer

Jan 2017 to Till Date

Client : Morgan Stanley Project: eReq Desktop

**UI** Developer

Angular 6, NGRX Platform (Store, Effects, Router-Store, Store-Devtools), RXJS, TypeScript,ALM/JIRA
Description: eReq Desktop is a Product of Morgan Stanley which is used to create requisition for a planned business trip.
eReqDesktop is a redesign project for the existing 3 Tier ASP.Net travel requisition application to Web API 2 services and
Angular 6 UI. The application development followed Agile methodology closely since the application is being showcased
for agile implementation in Morgan Stanley. The application provides a platform to create requisition for a planned business
trip and take the requisition through the different approvals required for the cost center. The requisition consists
of flight booking, hotel booking, car hire information, travel expense. The traveler will be
asked to justify exceptions through the life of the requisition e.g. flight/hotel booking, cost exceptions etc. Once the
requisition has been approved, the requisition is send for ticketing. In the approval workflow the application notifies
approvers via email about the pending approval request. Alternately the approver can log on to the eReqDesktop
application and view the pending approval requests. The approver can then approve or decline with justification as to why
the request was declined. If the approver approves the request the requisition moves on to the next level of approval or is
send for ticketing

Roles & Responsibility:

Analysis Module development requirement.

Development Phase for each Module.

Develop reusable component for various module.

Write Test Case for each Module using Jasmine and Karma

Ensuring all deadlines are met for all deliverables in timely manner and keeping client manager informed.

Daily Stand up meeting organizing.

#### dotCORD IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd as Software Developer

Oct 2015 to Feb 2017

Client: Morgan Stanley Project: FACT SCR Rewrite

**UI** Developer

Angular 4/ PhantomJS / HighCharts API ALM/JIRA

Description: It is a Product of Morgan Stanley Internally for their client for report generating tools, with lot of module for generating report. PDF report generation using phantomis.

Roles & Responsibility:

Analysis Module development requirement.

Development Phase for each Module.

Develop reusable component for various module.

Prepare for Test Case for each Module

Prepare PDF generation development for each module.

Ensuring all deadlines are met for all deliverables in timely manner and keeping client manager informed.

Daily Stand up meeting organization.

Capturing various metrics & analysis.

Firaa

Web Developer

Html 5, Bootstrap, JS, jQuery, Ajax, PHP, MySQL, Code ignitor MVC, Angular JS ( was used for building the prototype of the application)

Description: Android application designed specifically for travellers. It's an exclusively built to be easy and beautiful travel blogging app. Users can create their travel blog on the fly, during their trip. It has simplistic messenger like interface. Firaa creates the days and posts automatically. Users can create their blogs offline too, later all the posts can be synced automatically or manually. Every registered user on Firaa, has a web account through which they can manage all their travel blogs and share their travel blogs with world.

Roles & Responsibility:

Convert UI designs to html pages using Bootstrap

interaction of the html pages with backend using ajax, JavaScript & jQuery.

Validation using jQuery Plugin and integration of other jQuery Plugins.

CRUD operation using PHP and MYSQL

Prototype of Firaa:

Leveraged AngularJs resources for all data access, encapsulating URLs and standardizing data access from json response

AngularJs Controllers to maintain each view data.

URL: http://firaa.me/

#### IdeaFlask Solutions Pvt. Ltd. as Web Developer

Feb 2014 to Sep 2015

System Reservation

Web Developer

Html 5, Bootstrap, JS, Angular JS, python, mongo dB database

Description: It is a Single Page Application (SPA) developed for our Client. It has sensitive data so user can view only after connecting through VPN. Users can enter new records, edit records, delete records. User can navigate through different records by the pagination feature. User can select column or deselect column of the records to be viewed with the UI features created. User can sort single column or multiple column after checking the radio button. It has search feature. Roles & Responsibility:

Convert UI designs to html pages using Bootstrap

interaction of the html pages with backend using AngularJS & ¡Query.

Validation using AngularJS ngMessages and pagination using ui.bootstrap.pagination module.

Leveraged angularjs resources for all data access, encapsulating URLs and standardizing data access interfaces. Created custom directives for re - usable components.

Implemented AngularJS Controllers to maintain each view data. Implemented Angular Service calls using Angular Factory CRUD operation using AngularJS Python and mongo dB

#### **Education**

UG: B.Sc (Chemistry) from Karnataka University, Dharwad in 2006

PG: MCA (Computers) from Anna University in 2009

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular			
jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, JSON			
PHP, MySQL,MongoDB, SQL Server			
SVN, GIT, Putty, WinSCP, Jira, HP ALM			

## **Languages Known**

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Marathi				

### **Affirmative Action**

### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time